PRABHU MANIKANDAN

DATA SCIENTIST

Data Scientist with 2+ years of broad-based experience in building data-intensive applications, overcoming complex architectural, and scalability issues in diverse industries. Proficient in predictive modeling, data processing, and data mining algorithms, as well as scripting languages, including Python. Capable of creating, developing, testing, and deploying highly adaptive diverse services to translate business and functional qualifications into substantial deliverables.





phoenix11272@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/prabhu-manikandan-24295b167/



7010737393 / 9486337569



Erode, Tamil Nadu, India

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist Cognizant technology solutions

06/2019 - Present

Coimbatore.TN

- Developed image processing algorithms using machine learning & deep learning to segregate images that are sent to insurance companies (Image which contain obscene/unwanted images will be identified and moved to junk)
- Developed algorithms using Natural language processing for sentiment analysis on End-user feedback and helped organizations to work towards providing the best services.
- Build predictive modeling using various machine learning tools to predict the possibility of Server Restarts
- Developed action plans to mitigate risks in decision making while increasing profitability by leveraging data science
- Drive the interaction and partnership between managers to ensure active cooperation in identifying as well as defining analytical needs, and generating pull-through of insights with business.
- Built an SSRS report using the MSBI concepts like cleaning, analyzing & making it into usable information. Which helped organisation make efficient business-related decisions.
- Evaluated analytical model findings in the global monitoring reports.
- Developed a monitoring dashboard which help to monitor the various health status (Processor usage , Ram, disk usage) across different hosts for services
- Also Developed plethora of alerts and dashboards which sends us automated reports and alert emails based on different business requirement.

Data Analyst / Program Analyst trainee Cognizant technology solutions (Internship)

01/2019 - 06/2019

Coimbatore,TN

- Utilized analytical and technical expertise to provide insights and proposals to support business improvements
- Actively engaged in the quantitative analysis of sophisticated modeling to address business issues
- An active member of CRM team and created numerous dashboards which help the team and client understand daily case creation per client wise segregation and outcome in a visual manner
- Worked on Macros for automating daily routine jobs done using excel

GENERAL SKILLS

Data visualization

Machine learnning

Deep learnning

Data Preparation

Pattern recognition

Quality management

Statistical Analytics

Neural Networks

Regression Models

Classification models

K- Fold cross validation

XGBoost

Dimensionality reduction

TECHNICAL SKILLS

OPERATING SYSTEM:

Windows

Database/Server:

My SQL, SQL server

Programming Languages:

Python (Scikit -learn , Tensor flow , Keras) , C , C++ , splunk's SPL, SQL , XML/ HTML , VB-Macros

Other Software / Tools:

Tableau, AWS services, Dynamics, Snowflake, splunk, MSBI (SSIS, SSAS, SSRS), Microsoft office

CERTIFICATIONS

- Data science A-Z using python (Udemy)
- Tableau 2020 hands on training
- Machine learning Using Python
- Statistics for business Analytics
- Power BI Basics
- Neural Language processing (On-going)

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Computer Science Engineering Kumaraguru College of Technology

2015 - 2019

Coimbatore,TN

Higher Secondary Board Exams - 94.41% SKV Matriculation Higher Secondary School

2013 - 2015 Namakkal,TN

Matriculation Board Exams - 96.81% Vidhya Vikas Matriculation School

2013 Namakkal,TN

INTERESTS



Video game



Video Game Designing



Digital painting



Music